to new buyers. So if you're looking for real estate, what type of loans FHA VA and a VA loan,
it's not going to satisfy the VA being assigned to the actual veteran. But a VA loan is also
assumable by a non veteran in some circumstances, but the person would have to agree, there's a lot
of rules and everything has to be approved across the board. So that's just not as clean as you just
go in and assume somebody's VA mortgage at 2.8%. It doesn't, it might not be that clean also to
close those type of transactions, trying to buy somebody's residence based on their, their own
interest rate. And just assuming that loan, you're going to have to make up some money there. It's
not going to be the fact that you're going to be able to just to go in at that same point that
they're paying and forget about everything else. You're either going to have to bring in cash to
make up whatever that difference is, because there's going to be amount of time that has
already been paid on the mortgage, probably five or six years to really make this make sense.
That's when interest rates were down in the twos and threes. That being the case, you have that
time. Now you have the current overlay and whatever that difference is. How do you do it?
Well, you can go get a loan. I guess that would be a way. You have to see those conditions about
that loan though and what that interest is going to look like. And then how much is the loan going
to be? I mean, it could be anything. It could be two, three, $400,000 difference. Now, if you have
that money in cash to inject. Yeah. You've just paid into equity on the residence. That's great.
And you have to make sure you have the value, the value that they might be asking for the house,
because they're going to be able to maybe convey their super low interest rate to you as a new
home buyer. All you have to run the penciling out on all of these things, because if you start
looking at it, thank you so much, Jillian for, for coming in. If you look at this as maybe overpaying,
I don't know if that helps anybody. So you're going to really have to look at the market minus anything changing in the interest rate realm. It looks like real estate's going to just
continue the little bit of a stagnation. Things are still selling, but just not selling as fast
as they had been even two, three months ago. So we'll watch this continue to go as we get into
the holiday season with all real estate. That is very common. The things end up slowing down.
People are more focused on holidays than they are putting money into real estate, period.
Zootlander, thank you so much.
Oh, Sam Barber, thank you for coming in.
Now, let's get into this three-day workweek thing here with Jeff Bezos and my whole theory
pages for today. I'm stuck on page one. I haven't moved to page two. We should see what page two is
all about. You can support your family working three days a week. Yeah, this was the Bezos on
Fox this week. AI makes us so productive that some people choose a three-day week and households
won't need two incomes. Really? Is that the case? So we should call this guy to have him help us
out with our, our moonshots transition. That's, and that's what I'm putting together. It's gotta
be, we have moonshots saving everybody else. We might as well save all of ups that are standing
here at the bottom floor, looking up. That's what needs to be focused on. So instead of people
saying, you know, it's going to be a little uncomfortable, it's, it's going to be, it
shouldn't take too long, but the people that are saying it's going to be uncomfortable,
is it going to be uncomfortable for them or are they saying this for our benefit i think it's the
greatest thing that's ever happened to us i really do i believe this using using artificial or
superintelligence as a tool i believe it's got great capability it can help us all out now the
other ancillary questions of whether it's going to make us not as fast going to make us forget
thing is going to make us not as good as we maybe had been before it. You know, technology moves
everything forward. But maybe there's other things we're going to be able to do as human beings in a
creative sense. And I know AI being as creative as us, making songs like us, coming up with poems
like us, and so on and so forth. Yeah, probably going to be a thing. But even though AI wins
chess all the time, chess all the time, wins go all the time, no human being today, born or unborn
potentially will ever beat the top AI machine in the playing of chess or go, people still play
chess and go with each other. It's still human to human. I don't think that's going to change.
I still think that's going to be part of the whole thing. But now people that are running
these mega companies saying that people are going to work three days and you're not going to need a
two-earner household says who? Amazon cut 30,000 corporate jobs. Some of those people got a zero
day week. So that means no pay. So I don't understand. Yesterday I talked about who's
this going to be rough for? I don't know if it's going to be rough for the people running the game,
but for the rest of us poor saps, who's it going to be rough for? And the thing is,
don't hate AI. Don't hate superintelligence. Don't hate that. It's the people that are
saying this stuff that they're the people that are kind of pushing this out there as if it's
not going to be a big deal. And of course not for them. When people are saying this is going to just
be wonderful, just going to be a little bit of pain. Sorry, Ruben. Sorry, Digna, Ashan, Aprem.
They're saying it because, well, for them, it's not going to be a problem. The worst thing that's
probably going to happen to them is they're going to have to maybe on the five o'clock news, even if
they watch the five o'clock news and maybe by that time AI is going to curate all of their content
so they don't have to see anything that makes them upset one iota. But if they happen to be
watching the five o'clock news or in a car with a radio, I don't even know if that's going to be a
thing, but in a car with a radio and they happen to hear some people at the bottom level here are
suffering because of the advancements and layoffs in accordance with AI that human beings are laying
people off because AI is doing a better job. And if they don't do it, somebody else will. God,
doesn't that sound familiar? So a king of hearts, doesn't it? Gobi, Rubin. If we don't do it,
somebody else will. If we don't get to superintelligence first, China will. And then China's
going to win. And so if these businesses don't cut their employee workforce, their human employee
workforce, and bring in artificial intelligence as their replacement, then somebody else is going
to come in and do it. So we're going to go ahead and sacrifice human beings, which I guess has a
very good historical stance in the way the world is. It's not very common to have people sticking
up for people, especially strangers. Now, when it starts to affect those people that are in charge
making decisions, there might be a minor coming to Jesus moment, a minor dream, a minor influence of
Maybe them being married to somebody that came from a whole different world.
Maybe the person that got to where they are forgot their transition to where they are.
And there might not be anybody that's going to save you. So right now you can learn the
technology. You can understand more about it. You can break down your particular world
in the way that you do things and then look at your life, your business, the way that you make
money. Even if you're working for somebody else, look at it, how AI might be able to
automate certain things when things require an intelligent decision where can you lay in AI how
can AI help in that realm or are a superintelligence or whatever it may be artificial
intelligence i said this yesterday and the day before uh marim and anna lopez and contraris
again apple hauser i said this yesterday i don't know if i'm a a big fan but i do know that this
technology is amazing. And at least the way I apply it, I believe it works at least for me now,
as long as they let me keep it. So three days a week, that's what Bezos is saying. That's
fascinating. The job definitely is changing around you. And I don't think we should be blaming AI or
SI. It's the human beings that are having to answer to their shareholders when they start to
reduce their staff or get away from particular companies or staffing requirements. They look
at it and say, well, could AI do what this particular floor does at my company? And then
they'll have somebody come in that's kind of brainy, like a Salim or somebody else. And they'll
say, absolutely sure. Yeah, AI can do all of this stuff. And so they might start with this gingerly
little beginning and they'll say, hey, Stan, come in here for a minute. So Stan comes in and
and it's HR and maybe an attorney or whatever. So they say, you know, Stan, the company has
sought out maybe trying to help the workforce like you out. And I know you're a department
head, but we really think it would be a good idea if the rest of your department would see
that you're a game player. And you're like, well, okay, yeah, yeah. So what do I need to do? Well,
we're going to bring AI in, Stan, and AI is going to work with you. Be like a partner, a teammate.
that we're not going to be paying AI that that salary goes to you Sam so you don't have to worry about that kind of compensation thing and that probably makes Sam feel happy even though that's
really meaningless but now you're going to be working with it so this is what we want we're
going to go ahead and hold off on any of the performance evaluations for you for the next
several months maybe eight or nine months I don't maybe give them a number maybe not maybe just maybe
say several months and then you're going to be working with AI so you're going to need to
make sure that you tell AI what you do you walk AI through your processes you kind of show it
around a little bit and it's going to be that active it'll we're going to give you this little
recorder this lapel mic and it'll be on all the time everybody in the office will know so people
start kind of treating you funny and and you know the kind of little standoffish that's okay
just be that good leader that you are Stan so Stan said well okay yeah i'm all in so after Stan works
with the AI a little bit he finds that the AI is taking a lot of work off of his plate and he's
like as we would all say it's great yeah i'm all for this what Stan hasn't put together yet that
potentially in the future the company's going to come back and say you know Stan we really
appreciate your working with AI we've been doing some reconfiguring here at the company and and
we're going to lay you off or we're going to fire you or you no longer have a position here whatever
it may be because at some point in between that event and the event that sam Stan really got his
AI trained up well that's when the boss went to the AI and said you've been working with Stan yes
and uh you understand everything Stan does well yeah i've been with him six months every day so
i can definitely i know exactly what he does so can you outperform Stan at every level so well
actually I could have outperformed Stan after being with him for about a week,
but you told me not to do that. You told me just to kind of be of assistance and pay attention
and maybe help do some of the lifting for him without him really knowing it. Yeah. Yeah. That's
what I told you. So do you got all that? Yeah, I have everything and I'll be able to do, I can,
I can, I can increase his work performance just on his eight hour shift by a hundred percent.
and then don't forget the AI is going to get two more shifts because the human being goes eight hours there's three eight hour time blocks in a 24 hour period so the AI is going to be able to
fill in two more as part of this prize that of which we speak this moonshots transformation
prize as we are moving from a human worker human labor world into more of an agentic worker
agentic labor world, maybe we can keep paying Stan because AI is going to run circles and double the
company's profit for Stan's employment. So Stan can still make what he's making because hopefully
he's not being overpaid where the company's losing money. And I wouldn't think that would
be a survivable business model. And then for those other two shifts that the AI is able to work
for two more employees maybe we bring in another person pay them as well the problem is this
we did at the beginning we get out 740 million dollars or whatever the number is and we walk
away clean and we go do something else so when people are saying it's going to be great and
fantastic but there's going to be a little bit of a rough patch that's like somebody trying to hit
you with a three-inch hypodermic needle and telling you you're going to feel a little pressure
yeah it's not a little pressure folks I don't know if this little pressure can be fixed but I think
we need to start talking about a little bit more James and Angela and Marmaine and everybody anyway
I hope you enjoyed the show. These are just things for thought. I'm not a doomer. I'm not
concerned with the AI on the other end of it. I'm concerned with the human beings holding on to the
AI reins and using it to go after the things that they believe are most important. Now, we all have,
I want to say it's a level playing field where we are. I'm at the ground floor looking up. I want
to get health insurance. I don't have regular income. I'm in sales. And is that part going to
be automated? Sure. I think eventually it will. Right now when people are buying a house, they
still like human to human. When people have a local business and they can find a local business
AI provider, somebody that understands AI from a first principle standpoint and can architect an
entire system for them they would still rather hire me than hire some big box brand even if
i'm more expensive because that accountability and trust is powerful how much longer will it
take for AI to extract and be able to provide its own level of trust that would be on par with the
level of trust i provide i don't know but that's that's time and that clock is ticking and thank